All the time we talk about email
marketing, but what does
that even look like?
Today, I'm going to take you with me,
just not on the process of writing an
email.
I haven't even thought about what I'm
going to write the email about yet.
Oh, fuck, yeah.
Nutonic now available in Sainsbury's.
I'm getting a bit ill.
That's from that webinar last week,
I reckon. Getting up at the crack of dawn.
Okay, I swear to God,
I swear on my nan's life, she's dead,
I haven't even thought about this.
So I'm currently using Kit.
I really like Kit,
and I'm probably going to create an email
marketing course with
them. So as you can see here,
403,000 subscribers.
It's actually down a little bit.
I've been trying to shrink this list.
It costs me a [chuckles] fucking fortune.
So I'm about to message 403,000 people.
Now,
the offer is going to be relatively
generic.
So here I've got a template,
and within this template, I've just got,
"Bonjour." This is where I do the email.
So now from an ideation standpoint,
where can we go?
One of the first places I would look
is Facebook Memories,
which, no, you cannot see.
Because some of the stuff on here
is just... 15 years ago,
you could say that stuff.
Nowadays, you can't. I'd go jail
if Kier Starmer saw some of the stuff I
said here.
11 years ago,
"I've become much funnier in the last few
months and I don't know
how." All right. Bloody hell,
15 years ago, asking for an
orange two for one.
Do you remember two for one Wednesdays?
I've shown your age.
17 years ago, "James Smith
is gay." Someone's on my phone.
God, there's some stuff here. All right.
Let's just say the personal Facebook
is out of action.
We'll go to the business Facebook.
Let's have a look at our memories perhaps.
And it's all just a little bit boring.
Okay, next thing we need to do,
potentially go to the
camera roll. So what I'll do
is I'll just go...
A friend of mine didn't know the other day
that if you hard press the camera roll,
you can move through. So
when it comes to aftershave, they pick the
smell last. That's right.
So they will think to themselves, okay,
what's the branding? What's the name?
And they'll reverse engineer it.
So what I'm doing is I'm doing that.
I'm going to find a photo,
and then I'm going to reverse engineer it
to the point. Because what I want
is twofold,
as you'll find out in a second.
I want the image to start the story.
It's almost like a visual hook for how
it's going to begin.
Hmm, that's actually quite a good one.
Let's keep going.
If not, I'll come back to that.
The thing that wigs me out the most as
well
is when you go back through your camera
roll, you scroll such a long way to
find things that didn't feel
that long ago. It's almost a tragedy.
[inhales] What we got? How was that,
that long ago?
Found an old PT picture of me.
I'm not quite sure where we're going to go
with this
email yet, but let's give it a go.
And what a lot of people
sometimes... Well,
I actually can't speak on behalf of
people.
What I'll do is I will start with the
image.
I'll start writing
and often just delete a little bit.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm just going to make sure
that picture doesn't take up
too much of the screen. Now,
looking at that, this
is one of the only kind of rare
pictures that exist of me personal
training.
Here is one of the very rare pictures of
me
personal training. Back in my day,
it wasn't very cool
to record yourself doing it.
It's quite a nice image because you can
see the PT
shirt in the background
and got a functional training room.
Spent a lot of time in here just so I
didn't have to put up with everyone else.
So now I need to think of a lesson,
the way we're going to dial this back.
I'm going to want it to tie into Nutonic,
maybe even the coaching app, maybe even
the business mentorship side of things.
What could be a poignant lesson from
personal training?
I've got one right here. People think
that coaching people...
I tell you what I'm going to do.
I'm going to write it,
then I'm going to read it
back to you. Probably going to get
that SpongeBob one hour later.
One hour later. Okay,
so I'm going to read it from the top.
Always proofread your emails if you can.
Here is one of the very rare pictures of
me personal training.
Back in the day,
it wasn't very cool to record yourself
doing it. Eh.
Because that's the little pop of people
that kind of film everything in his PT.
People think that coaching,
helping businesses go online,
and even selling a
beverage brand are three different things.
They're not.
As a coach, I had one job,
to see where someone was.
Maybe let's underline that.
Someone might be getting bored in the
onset. To understand their goal.
Let's go this one,
maybe a little bit of italic.
And to seek the next progression from
there.
When I had those three things,
that's actually all I needed.
If someone can squat 20 kilograms,
the next progression isn't 100 kilograms,
even
if that's their goal. It's 22.5.
If someone's social media following
is 800, I
don't say, "Right,
let's get to 10,000." I'd say let's aim
for 810.
If our rate of sale for Nutonic in
Sainsbury's is 20,000 a week,
let's aim for
21,000. For each and every goal,
irrespective of where you are,
find those three
things, where you're at,
where you want to be,
what's the next step.
The only time you need a coach is
if you're not fully clear on where the
next step
is. If you know it, don't hire me.
Do it yourself,
and maybe set a more sensible
goal.
The person who wants to lose 10 kilograms
of fat will have a much happier
time losing one kilogram 10 times over.
Let's maybe add that's 10 wins on the way
to the same goal
versus one.
This is known as progressive overload,
and I disagree that it's a
fitness term.
It's how you win at everything, James.
Now,
the thing that I want to get from that
is people now will potentially read
this and they'll go, "Oh,
do you know what?
James is right." And it could make them
feel motivated, could make them feel
validated.
If you're a personal trainer reading that,
you're going to go, "Do you
know what? I'm going to use
that on my clients today."
And the idea of the email is
just to give someone a little insight.
I'll also put a link in the comments below
here, and in the description to join
this, just so you can copy them
if you ever wanted to copy them.
And it's a bit more difficult for me
because I'm trying to sell three things
off
the back of it.
I've also slightly mentioned
that Nutonic is available in
Sainsbury's, which means
that someone next time they're walking
down the street
will go,
[fingers snap] "Let me go check
if there's a can." So I've got that
subliminal sales in there.
And then I will always put the sale in the
PS. I've not done the title yet.
The good thing about Kit is I can
split test it.
Let me go, three things you need to win.
The only three things, maybe.
Let's maybe go with that.
And then what I might do
is I might split test this.
So we're going to subject lines.
The only three things you need to win at
life.
Maybe I'll go,
the only three things you need to win.
So I can now figure out whether
or not that at life bit actually improves
the
click-through rate, and maybe we'll go for
do these three things to succeed.
Let's do these three
things every day.
That might get a bit more curiosity. Okay,
cool.
So then I can put that in there.
Do duration for a few hours.
Go back, PS, try Nutonic.
Have my expert coaches run your training.
And what you might have seen there
is there is a keyboard shortcut where if I
type in a certain code,
you go to text replacement on Apple,
for any of you
that don't do this. So for instance,
especially when you need hyperlinks for
your
stories, you should all be having this.
So for instance, if I go Nutonic one,
then hit Space, it
prepopulates that. Hopefully, you guys
are all using that.
You're using that, right?
And then,
let me take your business online in 30
days
challenge small businesses. Pop this here,
go
here. Boom. Put that link in there
and then Nutonic.
Now,
you might be thinking I've done this
pretty naturally.
I've been doing this for a decade.
So although that's not the best email I've
ever
written, it's enough for people to go,
"Hmm, that's pretty good." And again, at
400,000, we might get 10,000 clicks
or whatever of people going through to
it. And ultimately, traffic
is the lifeblood that keeps your business
alive. So here you go.
Maybe I'll go more info.
Maybe a little down emoji. Dot point.
Lovely. Okay.
So from there,
I've got a draft of my email.
I click continue.
Well, actually, just before I do that,
copy. LinkedIn.
Oh, what's this guys? James Smith,
top voice. Don't worry about it.
So I can take that image
that I had before.
And the thing is,
if I'm going to write an email,
I might as well repurpose it
into a LinkedIn post. This
is where written content, to me, is
something that people sleep on. Now,
what's going to happen from
here is any of my LinkedIn posts
that do well, one of my members of
staff actually then goes
and repurposes it onto YouTube
and onto the
business Instagram page.
So I only really need to put these in one
place.
But again,
it's just a good idea to make sure that
if I'm going to create this
asset, which it is,
may not be the best asset because I'm
obviously just here
teaching you how to do it.
Why wouldn't you repurpose it?
Because although I am predominantly a
video content guy, it makes sense
that should I do written content,
it should go in more places.
Even if only, let's say,
one person joins this challenge, it's $999
for me. For me.
Other people get some of it, FTR,
for the record. Cool.
So I can copy that now and then I go to X.
Not that I'm very big on X, by the way.
I'm just having a pop. I'm seeing
if I can understand the platform.
Understand the platform. Boom.
That can go out there.
I've already got some posts scheduled,
so I'm probably going to push this one
back.
Let's go 8:00 PM for that one.
Do I care really what time it goes?
Just getting it out there.
And then to this email. Cool.
Hopefully, those links work.
I should probably test it.
But my email list know by now,
they're like, "Oh,
James just forgot to put the link
in properly." Send email.
Got my three subject lines I'm going to
test.
Send now. Why not? Boom, boom, boom.
403,000 subscribers.
Cool.
And then the only other thing you need to
know is that really, I just have to
create a little page.
I've not really used it that much.
So when you click,
you'll get through to this.
This is a page that I can edit within Kit,
and people can sign up in there
and join the list. So
when you click the link in the
description, you get that.
So there really is how to write an email
marketing email. Screengrab. All right.
That is behind the scenes of how you write
an email marketing email.
It's not sexy, but it works. Fuck yeah.
All right, that was that.
Bye-bye.